dclibrary.org 2018-12-30

# Privacy and Security | District of Columbia Public Library

The DC Public Library is committed to protecting the privacy of all visitors to our Website through the following practices. 

**Collection and Use of Online Information**  
When you visit our Website, certain data, such as your computer's unique Internet protocol (IP) address, will be automatically collected and sent to the servers that support our Website system to help us provide better service and a more effective Website. In addition, as part of these efforts, sections of this site may place a small text file (typically only a few bytes) on your hard drive to allow us to identify your computer. We will not attempt to read any additional information on your hard drive, and we do not combine collected information with other personal information to determine your identity or your e-mail address.

In order to visit certain areas of this site, or to use certain services, you may be asked to provide personal information, such as your name, address, or gender. If you are making a payment, we may ask for your credit card number and billing address. If you decline to provide requested information, our ability to serve you may be limited. But you will still be able to visit the site and take advantage of the wealth of information it offers. 

**Secure Transmissions** ****  
Please be assured that this site is equipped with security measures to protect the information you provide us. We encrypt credit card numbers and other data that must remain secure to meet legal requirements.

**Protection of Personal Information**  
Your individual identifying information will not be shared, sold, or transferred to any third party without your prior consent, or unless it is required by law. It is available to District Web development employees only for the purpose of maintaining the DC.Gov web portal and improving the site visitor experience. 

In addition, the confidentiality of library materials selected and reviewed by library customers is protected pursuant to D.C. Official Code § 39-108 (2001 Ed.).

**Other Sites** ****  
The DC Public Library’s privacy policy extends to the library’s Website only. If you access another organization's Website through the dclibrary.org Website, you should read that organization's privacy policy to determine its Website practices.
